Brett Valley

TECHNICAL WRITER | EDITOR

Durham, NC brett.valley@gmail.com (646) 651-6245 LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

Profile

Intellectually curious technical writer, editor, and content strategist with 20+ years bringing ideas to life through words. Technically proficient self-starter with the ability to communicate at all levels of an organization. Works cross-functionally to create, develop, and publish user support and education materials, websites, and other information-heavy deliverables.

Skills

- Technical Writing
- Developmental Editing
- Copyediting
- Content Strategy

- Microsoft Suite
- Google Suite
- DITA, oXygen
- Madcap Flare

- GitHub / GitHub Pages
- Software Documentation
- Information Architecture
- Website Development

Education

Certificate, Technical Writing

Duke University Continuing Education, Durham, NC

Bachelor of Arts, English Literature

The University of Georgia, Athens, GA

Study Abroad, English Literature

Oxford University, Oxford, England

Technical Writing Experience

Senior Technical Writer/Editor (Contract)

VA Health Systems via BAC, Stafford, VA (Remote)

July 2020 - Present

- Develop technical reports and presentations on health software products for Chief Health Information Officers. Collate content, harmonize various authors into one consistent voice, and edit for clarity and readability, reducing content by 40%.
- Write quarterly newsletter articles, learning new topics and collaborating with a SME to deliver relevant content.
- Created templates and developed an internal style guide.
- Synthesized source information for new website content for VA Health Systems.
- Wrote and edited content for a UX Guide website.

Technical Writer, Content Strategist & Web Writer

2020 - 2021

ExactlyIT, Durham, NC

- Wrote technical documents, performed substantive editing, and managed the content strategy and information architecture of a new website.
- Crafted market-friendly copy for local businesses.

Technical Writer/Editor (Contract)

2019

Duke University Population Research Institute, Durham, NC

- Developed the content strategy, information architecture, and content audit for 3 websites whose primary purpose was to generate research funding: the Duke Population Research Institute (DUPRI) and its affiliated centers, Duke Population Research Center (DPRC) and the Duke Center for Population Health and Aging (CPHA).
- Improved the clarity and user-friendliness of website content through writing and editing.

Technical Writer/Editor (Contract)

2018 - 2019

Duke University Benefits, Durham, NC

- Crafted friendly, clean, and informative communications about a major and unpopular benefits change for distribution to all Duke University faculty and staff.
- Developed the content strategy for the plan's website redesign, which led to being seen as an integral part of the development team.
- Overhauled the existing Duke Benefits Summary Plan Description Guide and updated edited the content for internally distribution to all faculty and staff.

Other Professional Experience

Owner, R. Brett Valley, LLC

2018 - Present

Freelance Writing & Editing (Remote)

Owner and sole proprietor specializing in technical writing and editing, book editing, coaching, and consulting.

Co-founder, Writer & Editorial Director

2011 - 2019

Yardarm Media, Durham, NC

- Co-founded company that specialized in writing, editing, marketing, communications, and content strategy.
- Personally provided a full range of editorial services for authors to submit to literary agents, publishers, or to self-publish.
- Solely performed business development, generating revenue by bringing in new business.
- Crafted marketing material, communications, website content, and social media posts.

Editor 2006 - 2009

Three Rivers Press/Crown Books (Random House) & Gotham Books (Penguin), New York, NY

- Acquired and edited several New York Times bestselling books.
- Managed and mentored an editorial assistant.
- Wrote promotional copy and coordinated editorial and production processes.

Affiliations & Volunteer

Member, Society for Technical Communications

Writer & Editor, Member, Communications Committee, political advocacy group (2021 – Present)

Weekly Volunteer, Durham Scrap Exchange (2017 – 2018)